When the snow falls onto the lights,
it blurs them and makes them
sparkle even more.
I just love seeing that.
That's another reason why I love the snow.
Huh? Did I say something weird?!
No...
I was just happy to hear you say
you loved me, Master Hitoyoshi.
I know you were only referring
to my namesake, but...
It felt good to hear it anyway.
Huh?
Huh?!
I wonder what the definition of love is.
In the past...
I once confessed my love to a girl
I used to hang out with all the time.
And she said to me...
Hitoyoshi, what you're feeling isn't love.
It's just a desire for companionship.
That's all.
And I thought...
Come to think of it, yeah.
I had been desperately lonely,
and I felt as though talking to her
saved me from that.
That was why I'd confessed to her.
After that, we never hung out again.
My confession probably hurt her,
and her response certainly hit me harder
than a regular refusal would have.
But if what she said was true,
and that feeling wasn't love,
then what is it that I'm feeling right now?
Yokoya
Episode 11: Your Prayers are the Gods' Prayers.
Good morning, Master Hitoyoshi.
Morning...
Ugh... No, this is all my fault.
It's all my fault!
Ms. Yuki's been having nightmares
recently, so I told her...
Well, if you wanna sleep next to me,
just say the word!
I can't believe I just blurted out
something like that!
And I hate my past self for saying it!
I haven't been able to get a wink of sleep!
I can't take much more of this, physically...
and given that we're together more often due
to winter break, the timing couldn't be worse!
Master Hitoyoshi.
Is something the matter?
No, no... I just wanted to get an early start
on the end-of-year cleaning.
As if... What a terrible excuse.
What am I even doing?
I have to put a stop to this.
For my sake and Ms. Yuki's.
I'm sorry, Hitoyoshi.
But even if I were to tell
Ms. Yuki my feelings...
Nothing would happen, right? I mean, she's...
Mopping...
is the one thing I haven't tried
since the day I arrived here.
Horrible Blunder
I blundered horribly at the time, but...
Today is my chance to redeem myself.
I'll clean this place till it sparkles!
Maybe then, Master Hitoyoshi will cheer up.
Ms. Yuki...
Any other trash to throw out?
Déjà vu...
I can't apologize enough...
It's okay. I know it's our furry friend's fault.
Hey! Don't cause trouble for Ms. Yuki.
That said, Ms. Yuki really hasn't changed.
I cleaned the bath in the morning,
so you... can take...
Master Hitoyoshi?
Oh...
Ah... Um...
I-I'll go run the bath!
Nothing's changed on Ms. Yuki's side.
Though she's matured as a person,
she's still just as genuine
and sincere as the day we met,
and she treats us all as family in the
same way I've always found comfort in.
And now...
Am I really going to ruin all that?
I'm sorry, Hitoyoshi.
Hitoyoshi, you're probably just lonely.
I never want to feel that way again.
And I don't want Ms. Yuki to leave me, too.
Master Hitoyoshi, are you all right?
You've been acting strangely since
this morning, so I was wondering...
Have you caught some manner of illness?
Oh, no!
I just hurried off because I wanted
to get the bath filled quickly...
Ah! I know that smile!
That's her "I have prepared
my lap for you" face!
Ms. Yuki, you shouldn't be doing that
when my feelings are all messed up!
And what's with those puppy-dog eyes?!
I need to get out of this, at least for now!
Um... I've been thinking about
this for a while, but...
The whole resting my head on your lap thing...
It's kind of embarrassing...
Normally, you know...
a high school boy would only ask a girl
to do something like that
if he had more bravery
than sense... or, like...
You're fed up with me,
aren't you, Master Hitoyoshi?
No! That's not what I meant!
I understand. After all...
I can't do anything right.
Ms. Yuki... You're...
Huh?
Wh-What? My eyes... They feel hot...
They're hot, but water is coming out of them!
Are these...
Sorry! I didn't mean to make you...
I promise I'm not fed up with you,
or anything of the sort!
I made her cry.
What do I do? What should I do?!
Tends to run away
when things get bad
I don't know!
I don't know anything!
Self-esteem
But I know it's my fault.
Oh... I know! The bath!
I don't want you to catch a chill,
so why don't you go use the bath?
Yes, you're right.
I shall do just that.
Wait, what am I saying,
sending her off to the bath?!
This isn't the time for that!
That was the worst possible choice!
Seriously, what was I thinking?
I just made things even more
awkward between us.
Yokoya
Ever since then,
Huh... Did you forget to buy daikon radishes?
Well, we can make do without them.
whenever anything happened,
I... I'm sorry!
Ms. Yuki's tears would flood out
through the dam I'd broken.
And so, not knowing how to repair it again...
Did he put on weight again?
I'm sorry!
I've just been doing the best
I can not to make her sad.
I'm sorry...
Huh...
It's taking all my attention.
I'm sorry...
Uh...
That one really wasn't your fault, Ms. Yuki.
I-If it's to stop her tears,
sleeping next to each other is no exception!
Oh... Y-You can't sleep?
I cannot.
61... 67... 71... 73...
Two sleepless nights later,
as a new day begins...
1,091... 1,093... 1,097... 1,103... 1,109...
New Year's Eve is finally upon us.
I'm so sleepy.
But I was able to clean up my room,
thanks to Ms. Yuki...
I-I'll be sure to do better next... year...
December 31st (Fri.)
Mmm...
So soft...
Master Hitoyoshi, I was thinking of picking up
something for dinner on my walk...
Master Hitoyoshi?
"I'll be back in a bit"?
See you next year!
Yeah! Happy New Year!
We will be closed
until the new year.
Sincerely, Management
Katsuda Side Dish Store
I'm sorry. We're all out of New Year's soba.
Soba
Oh, I see.
Um... Er...
Our special end-of-year sale is on now!
New Year's osechi boxes are over here!
People move so differently
when the year's almost over.
You have a good eye, young lady.
That's high-quality roast beef.
How many grams? Unsliced?
Very good! I'll give you a little extra!
Yokoya
Master Hitoyoshi, I've returned.
Welcome home!
I picked up something for dinner
while I was out walking.
Huh, really?!
I was thinking we could have your
favorite okonomiyaki tonight, Ms. Yuki!
And...
Ta-dah!
I bought some roast beef, too!
Roast beef...
Yokoya
Ms. Yuki! Ms. Yuki!
Well, they're not exactly the same.
Mine is sliced, and yours isn't!
Oh, man, that looks good!
Oh... You don't have to force
yourself to eat the lot, okay?
Okay.
Well, let's eat!
Let us eat...
It's delicious...
Yeah, it's great!
Seriously, what am I doing?
I still ended up making her cry.
I need to keep it together.
Dad gets home tomorrow, after all.
Ms. Yuki! Big Brother!
Yokoya
Happy New Year!
Next stop: our New Year's shrine visit!
Good morning, Ms. Riko.
Are you guys ready?
Let's go!
Well...
I was just calling for him, but...
He's not waking up at all?
Yes. He seems utterly exhausted.
Ah... That's gonna be a problem.
What is the matter?
Oh, he didn't tell you?
Big Brother's birthday is
January 1st. That's today!
Master Hitoyoshi's birthday?
Yup! So it's a family tradition to get together
after the shrine visit every New Year.
Master Hitoyoshi's birthday...
Well, we don't usually
give presents or anything,
so I guess he doesn't actually
have to be here for it...
I didn't... even know... his birthday...
I've never heard tears make that noise before!
More to the point, I've never
seen you cry before, Ms. Yuki!
Yes... You see...
Apparently...
It seems some kind of dam
within me has broken.
Yokoya
Seriously?!
Because of that, I'm now liable to
start crying for any reason at all,
so perhaps it would be best
if I, too, stayed home.
Gotcha!
Don't push yourself too hard!
I was planning to meet up with some
friends anyway, so I'll be fine!
Okay, see you later!
From Ms. Naka?
January 1st (Sat.)
"Will you and Yokoya be coming
to the shrine today?"
Former Assassin,
Currently Speaking
to a Text Message
I... was thinking of staying at home...
January 1st (Sat.)
"I'd really like it if we could visit together."
Visit the shrine...
with Ms. Naka...
Oh, Ms. Yuki!
Happy New Year!
So you came after all!
Your outfit's so cute!
Is it just you?
Yes.
In truth, I am not familiar with this
"New Year's shrine visit" tradition...
Huh?!
So you don't know how to pray at a shrine?
Yes. I'm afraid I have very
little experience in this area.
On New Year's,
it's traditional to visit a shrine so you can
convey your wishes for the year to the gods.
Oh, I see.
What are those white papers?
Those are fortune slips.
Each one has a fortune written on it
that applies to the new year.
Do you want to give it a try?
Yes...
Being able to help out another person
by explaining things they don't know...
It's almost like we're friends!
Oh, wait, we already are friends.
Oh, I got great luck—
What?!
D-Did she just go "boo-womp"?
Seriously? Boo-womp?!
I-It looks like the tears aren't stopping...
W-Would you like to sit down somewhere?!
Fortune Slip
Potential Luck
Desires: Will come true if you are patient.
Awaited Person: Will not show themselves for now.
Lost Item: Will remain missing and pass to another.
Business: No changes, either profit or loss.
Academics: Be sure not to neglect your studies.
Disputes: You may have difficulty gaining the upper hand.
Romantic Partner: They are a good person. Believe in them.
Moving Residency: Your current residence is ideal.
Sickness: Will recover. Seek a good doctor.
Marriage Prospects: If you wait calmly, your doubts will clear,
and that which you envision will come to pass.
My lost item "will remain missing
and pass to another"...
I bet... Master Hitoyoshi and I...
will be separated...
That can't be right!
But I really do feel like Master Hitoyoshi
has been acting differently.
He's been so standoffish with me lately.
Potential Luck
What if... it's only a matter of time before
Master Hitoyoshi no longer needs me...
and I'm not able... to be with him anymore?
When I think things like that...
I can't stop my tears from flowing.
If Master Hitoyoshi...
begins to hate me... whatever... shall I....
Um... You're not alone in that.
I've had times when my tears
wouldn't stop, too.
You have, Ms. Naka?
Yes, though it was when I was little.
It was after my mother passed away.
Oh! I didn't mean to make you sad again!
But at that time, I remembered something
my mother had told me.
We cry when we need to let out
sad feelings from inside of us.
So cry as much as you need to.
I bet the reason why your tears won't stop
is that all the sad feelings you've bottled
up inside you are flowing out at once.
That's why crying is nothing to be ashamed of!
At times like these, you should cry and cry
until you've let all the sadness out!
And then, one day you'll get your smile back!
I was the same way!
Ms. Naka...
When you calm down, let's go say our prayers
and have the gods do something
about that fortune of yours!
Here's how you pray at a shrine.
You bow twice,
and then you clap twice.
Ms. Riko, Ms. Naka, and Master Hitoyoshi...
They're always looking out for me.
I wish to be able to stay with them all,
this year and forever.
Incoming Call
Dad
I've gone to the shrine.
-Yuki